hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to discuss
about a useful tool which is available
in the Tosca Commander through which you
can perform a set of actions on a buffer
now this tool is known as buffer viewer
and this is present inside the tools
section so here you will see the buffer
viewer tool and we have already seen how
we can create different buffers either
you can use the t-box set buffer module
or you can also use the action mode
buffer to buffer a particular value
which is like a temporary variable right
so uh if I open this buffer viewer you
will see a separate window opens and
this basically provides me with all the
different buffer names and values which
I have created anytime in my workspace
and the interesting part about this
particular tool is that you can not only
view the buffers which have been created
you can also change or modify the
buffers okay so you can buffer uh modify
the buffer name or buffer value you can
also search with a particular buffer
Okay so
if I search with something like X you
will say it will search all the buffers
which have this particular word or this
particular character okay
okay so let's look with an actual
example let's create a buffer and then
let's see how we can do some changes on
that particular buffer using this buffer
viewer okay
so I have created a test case here it is
using the key box set buffer module and
as you can see I'm setting a buffer
called temp I'm giving it a value 10
okay so very simple test and I'm going
to run this now
so that should be done in a few seconds
and the buffer with name temp has been
set to value 10 okay
and now if I come here in the buffer
viewer and I go and search that
particular buffer called temp okay
you will see I can find this particular
buffer here right
now uh what all I can do on this
particular buffer or any other buffer
for that matter right so I can go ahead
and I can actually change the name of
this buffer I can even change the value
of this buffer okay
and then that will be saved uh whatever
changes I have done it will be
implemented uh immediately okay so now
that buffer name was changed to 10.23
and the value was changed to 20.
now I can even create a new buffer okay
so I can go to the next line and then
there is the edit option so I can say
temp okay and then again I can put a
value called 10.
okay so I can add as many buffers as I
want I can modify the existing buffers
okay and I can even delete the buffers
okay so for example if I now select
these two buffers or some other existing
buffer okay
so press on control and then select
multiple buffers here and then just
press delete from your keyboard okay
and you will see that those buffers have
been deleted
so these are all the operations you can
perform on the buffered viewer tool you
can search for a particular buffer you
can add new buffers you can modify the
existing buffers okay
and you can also delete or remove the
existing buffers okay so it's an useful
tool if you are working on buffers and
there are lots of buffers which have
been used in your particular project or
workspace you can look at all those
buffers uh in the buffer viewer
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video